CONTACT

- Mobile/WhatsApp: 0715199081 ☐ Email: gohole.arthur@gmail.com
- LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/goholearthur-3b159a51
- **Blog:** goholearthur.blogpost.com
- **Skype:** gohole.arthur

TOP SKILLS

- Public Health
- Health Promotion
- Monitoring and Evaluation
- Research
- Policy Making
- Climate Change
- Waste Management

LANGUAGES

- English (Full Professional)
- Kiswahili (Native or Bilingual)
- Luhya (Native or Bilingual)

CERTIFICATIONS

- Wash
- Monitoring And Evaluation

HONORS-AWARDS

• Proactive Leadership (EHSAMU)

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

- Association of Public Health Officers (APHOK Private Branch)
- Water Supply and Sanitation Collaborative Council (WSSCC)
- World Youth Alliance (WYA)
- Young Africa Leadership Network(YALI)
- Moi University Alumni Network
- Kenya Red Cross Society
- Environmental Health Association of Moi University- Secretary General (2011-2012)

GOHOLE AKARANGA ARTHUR

Environmental Health Specialist

SUMMARY

I am a highly skilled, versatile and creative Professional with eight years' experience in the Public Health Sector. I present wide range of experience in providing Environmental Health Solutions in a multi-sectoral settings for both government and donor funded projects. Over the years I have continuously been involved in monitoring and evaluation for a number of public health projects. In the process I have been able to gain much understanding for key monitoring and evaluation concepts for various funding models such as Global Fund, USAID, DFID & the recent being a Turnkey flagship Project.

I have also been able to learn and share experience in policy making especially in healthcare waste, pollution control and climate change in Kenya. This provided an opportunity where I was selected as one of the pioneers behind the establishment of National Healthcare Waste Management Public Private Partnership Framework and National Healthcare Waste Management Monitoring and Evaluation Framework, (2017 to 2019). Previously in 2016 I had also been involved in the review of the National Standard Operating Procedures for Healthcare Waste Management, Injection Safety Communication Strategy zero draft and Menstrual Hygiene Management Policy zero draft. I am currently a master trainer of trainers on healthcare waste management in the country with biasness to non-burn technologies. I am also a master trainer on community led-total sanitation monitoring and evaluation database in the country.

Professionally I am qualified public health specialist with a Bachelor of science degree in environmental health from Moi university. I am also a holder of other professional trainings such as monitoring and evaluation for health projects with biasness to HIV, climate change and sustainable agriculture.

My career objective is to be a reliable expert in environmental health sector who strives to utilize available limited resources to meet the "One Health Concept" demands for the global communities. I am very passionate towards strengthening of Public Private Partnership in the health sector with aim of promoting services delivery through high impact Health Investments. I am also a passionate career guide with abilities to design and conduct environmental health mentorship sessions for adolescents, youth and young adults in secondary and tertiary institutions.

PROFESSIONAL TRININGS

Global E-Health / USAID, (2013)

• Monitoring & Evaluation Of HIV Programs ·

Measure Evaluation/ USAID, (2013)

• Monitoring & Evaluation ·

UNDP-Amkeni (2014)

• Knowledge Management and IEC in Organization

Global Fund R10, Kenya Redcross Society & Public Health And Development Consultancy- IPHDC (2014)

• Quality Improvement in HIV/AIDs Programs,

Ministry Of Health (2016)

• Master Trainer: Use of non-burn Technologies in Medical Waste Management

- Master Trainer: Use of M&E database on Community Led- Total Sanitation
- Master Trainer: Climate Change and Health
- Community Led- Total Sanitation master Certifier

EXPERIENCE

NIKO GREEN

WASTE MANAGEMENT, CLIMATE CHANGE AND HEALTH

January – up to date (Short-Term)

Nairobi (National Coverage)

Working as Director responsible for Waste Management, Climate Change and Health Initiatives/Projects.

Coordinate with Niko Green Team in Establishing/Reviewing the Strategic Framework and Implementation plans for Waste Management, Climate Change and Health.

Planning, Monitoring and Evaluation for Waste Management, Climate Change and Health Initiatives/ Projects

Liaise with the Ministry of Health and the Ministry of Environment on matters Waste Management, Climate Change and Health.

Networking between Niko green and other stakeholders on matters Waste Management, Climate Change and Health.

Member- Climate Change, Energy and Health Technical Working Group

Member- Healthcare Waste Management Technical Working Group

Member- Environmental Health Policy, Advocacy and Research Technical Working Group

AMB Ecosteryl

MEDICAL WASTE NON-BURN TECHNOLOGIES-AMB MICROWAVE PROJECT IN KENYA

October 2016 - 2018 (3 years)

Nairobi (National Coverage)

Referred by the Ministry of Health Unit to Coordinate Activities under AMB Local Agent in Kenya (Vida) on the Implementation of Medical Waste Microwave Technologies in High Burden Facilities across Kenya and East African Countries. This include working closely with the Ministry of Health as owner of the Technology in the Country, the National Treasury and the Council of Governors. Ten Microwave Units are installed in 10 different sites including Kenyatta National Hospital, Moi Teaching and Referral Hospital, Nakuru PGH, Kakamega Country Referral Hospital, Jaramogi Oginga Odinga Referral Hospital Kisumu, Kisii Level 6 Hospital, Embu Level 5 Hospital, Nyeri level 5 Hospital, Machakos level 5 Hospital and Port Reitz Level 4 Hospital in Mombasa County.

Coordinate with Other stakeholders to improve the Management of Healthcare Waste in Kenya through the Use of Non-Burn Technologies Contribute to Stakeholders Forums on Healthcare Waste Management, Climate Change and Health in Kenya

Ministry of Health-Kenya

HEALTHCARE WASTE, POLLUTION CONTROL AND CLIMATE UNIT 2016 - 2016 (1 year)

Afya House: Nairobi (National Coverage)

Offer Technical Support Services to the Pollution Control, Waste Management and Climate Change Unit under the Division of Environmental Health and Sanitation

Golin Solutions

PRIVATE RESEARCH AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH SERVICES

January 2015 - 2016 (2 years)

Western Region- (Kakamega, Uasin Gishu and Bungoma)

- Technical Advisor and Resource Mobilization Focal Person- Mwangaza Africa International Mission- Eldoret
- Resource Mobilizer-Urafiki Kenya- Matete
- Board Member & Resource Mobilizer- Friends of Orphans and Vulnerable Persons(FOVUP)- Matunda
- Private Research Services- (NGOs & Phd)-Together with other Public Health Specialists
 we provide input to clients seeking our technical input in running their Public health
 related projects

REPACTED Kenya

GLOBAL FUND ROUND 10: HIV/AIDS-NAKURU COUNTY

November 2013 - 2015 (3 years)

Nakuru County

During this period I was able to coordinate a number of projects, Provide strategic leadership and direction to staff apart from the provision of technical support to the Director. Projects I supervised and reported to the director/ donors included:

- Global fund Round 10 on HIV management (sub-recipient) in Nakuru North district.
- Global fund Round 9 on TB management (SSR) Molo and Kuresoi Sub-Counties
- UNDP -Support to Devolved Governance in Kenya, Nakuru County
- RUSH Foundation- Economic Empowerment of Young People Living with HIV-Nakuru County

Kenya Red Cross

GLOBAL FUND ROUND 10: HIV/AIDS-COAST REGION

May 2013 - October 2013 (6 months)

Coast Regional Office (Mombasa, Kilifi, Kwale, Tana River, Lamu and Taita Taveta)

Worked under Global Fund Round 10 Unit-Coast Region and reported directly to the Regional Monitoring and Evaluation Officer.

- Improving lives of People living with HIV (PLHIV)
- Prevention of mother-to-child transmission (PMTCT)
- Curbing Stigmatization among Most at Risk Populations (MSM, Sex
- Workers, IDUs)
- Post Exposure Prophylaxis
- Anti-Jigger Campaings (Mombasa and Malindi)

Moi University

SECRETARY GENERAL- ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH STUDENTS ASSOCIATION OF MOI UNIVERSITY

2011 - 2012 (2 years)

Eldoret- Uasin Gishu County

Environmental Health Students Association of Moi University

Moi University/AMPATH/PERIPERI

THE USE OF MAGADI SODA ON TREATMENT AND PREVENTION OF TUNGA PENETRANS -JIGGERS

2011 - 2012 (2 years)

Webuye- Bungoma County

Research Assistant- Anti-Jiggers Peri Peri Project

CAFOD

REHABILITATION PROGRAMME FOR IDPS THROUGH SUSTAINABLE AGRICULTURE

March 2008 - April 2009 (1 year 2 months)

Lugari- Kakamega County

Acted as Field Officer in Lugari Sub-County. Focused on both Food and Animal production in a more sustainable way

Ministry of Gender and Children Affairs

EMPOWERNMENT OF ORPHANS AND VULNERABLE CHILDREN

October 2008 - March 2009 (6 months)

Lumakanda-Kakamega County

Recruitment of Orphans and Vulnerable Children into the Sub-County Database

EDUCATION

Moi University- Eldoret (2009 - 2013)

Bachelor Of Science (B.Sc.) Environmental Health Science (Public Health)

Baraka Agricultural College-Molo (2008 - 2008)

Certificate in Sustainable Agriculture (Crop and Animal Health)

St. Ignatius Mukumu Boys, Kakamega County

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education -KCSE (2004-2007)

Mapengo Primary School Lugari Kakamega County

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education- KCPE (1996-2003)

REFEREES

Dr. JAMES MWITARI- PhD, Msc Deputy Director of Public Health

Division of Environmental Health Ministry of Health HQ Cathedral Road, Afya House PO Box 30016-00100, Nairobi, KENYA

Personal Mobile: +254 721743502 Personal E-Mail: jmwitari@gmail.com

Mr. ROBERT KIBII Director- County Department of Tourism and Gender in Trans Nzoia

Former:

County Community Strategy Focal Officer ,Office of Public Health in Trans Nzoia County

Personal mobile: (254) 0722 296388 Email: rrkibii2012@gmail.com

Mr. LOLEM B. LOKOLILE Head- Climate Change and Pollution Control Unit

Division of Environmental Health Ministry of Health HQ, Cathedral Road, Afya House PO Box 30016-00100, Nairobi, KENYA Personal Mobile: +254 722589995

Personal Mobile: +254 722589995 Personal E-Mail: lokolile@gmail.com

Mr. MOSES SEGO

Sub County Public Health Officer- Lugari Kakamega County Department of Health Former:

Regional APHOK Tresurer, Western Kenya

TEL: 0721256419/0717829599 Email: mosesego@gmail.com